Guide to the Records of the Office of the Associate Dean of the School of Education (Louis Kleinman) RG 26.0.1.1
New York University Archives
Records of the Office of the Associate Dean of the School of Education (Louis Kleinman)
Bulk, 1969-1971
1966 - 1972
RG 26.0.1.1
New York University Archives
5.0 boxes
The Records of the Office of the Associate Dean of the School of Education contain mostly correspondence and memoranda between various School department heads and faculty and the Office of the Associate Dean, usually represented either by Dr. Elliot Mininberg, or the Associate Dean himself, Dr. Louis Kleinman. The memoranda are frequently budgetary in nature, requesting money allocation for departmental needs. There are also a number of different School of Education publications representing the interests and goals of the School's various departments.
Scope and Content
The Records of the Office of the Associate Dean of the School of Education spans 1962 to 1970, with most materials falling between 1967 and 1969. It is divided into three series: Series I: Departmental Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda; Series II: General Administrative Records; Series III: School of Education Publications. Series I is arranged alphabetically by department and consists of general correspondence and requests for funding for various projects between department heads and faculty and the Office of the Associate Dean as represented by either Dr. Elliot Mininberg (Director of Administrative Services and Assistant to the Associate Dean) or Associate Dean Kleinman himself. Series II contains a lot of general memoranda including a good deal from the Department of Administration and Supervision. Also included are copies of form letters and requests (both paid and unpaid) for budget allocations for food services and flyer/leaflet/pamphlet publication. Series III contains more correspondence dealing specifically with School of Education publications as well as copies of many of the publications themselves, primarily from 1968 and 1969.
This collection will be of use to those interested in the history of NYU's School of Education as well as the development of educational programs in the 1960s and 70s. The collection is reflective of the diversity of options available to students interested pursuing a career in education during this era.
Access Restrictions
Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection.
Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted.
Please contact the University Archivist with specific questions regarding restrictions.
Arrangement
Arrangement of the collection reflects the relative original order in which it was received. It has been divided into three series: Departmental Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda, General Administrative Records, and School of Education Publication.
Biography of Dr. Louis Kleinman
Dr. Louis Kleinman graduated from NYU with a bachelor of Science in 1948. He received a Master of Arts degree from Harvard University in 1949 and returned to NYU to earn his doctorate in education, which he received in 1959. Prior to earning his doctorate, he joined the staff at NYU in 1952 as Director of Educational Placement Services. From 1955 to 1960 he served as director of the Camden division of Rutgers University's School of Education. Kleinman returned to NYU in 1960, becoming head of the Teacher Education Section of NYU's Experimental Teaching Center. In 1961 he became head of the School's Center for Field Research and School Services. Kleinman retained this position when, in 1967, he was named to the new post of Associate Dean for Research, Field and Administrative Services.
Related Materials
Guide to the Administrative Files of the Dean of the School of Education, Daniel E. Griffiths, 1948-1985 (Bulk 1965-1983) RG 26.0.1
Conant, Howard; Griffiths, Daniel Edward, 1917-; Kleinman, Louis; Mininberg, Elliot I.; New York University. School of Education, Health, Nursing, and Arts Professions.; New York University. School of Education.; Steinhardt School of Education. Department of Occupational Therapy.
- Series I: Departmental Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Art Education, Dept. of, 1967 - 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Behavioral Sciences, 1968 - 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Communications in Education Program, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Creative Arts, 1968 - 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Dance Program, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Educational Psychology, Dept. of, 1967 - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Educational Sociology & Anthropology, Dept. of, 1968 - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Educational Theatre Program, 1968 - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Educational Theory & Application, Dept. of, 1969 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Elementary Education, 1967 - 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: English & Speech, 1967 - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Foreign Languages, 1967 - 1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Guidance & Personnel Administration, Dept. of, 1967 - 1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Hebrew Culture Program, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Higher Education, Dept. of, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: History & Philosophy of Education, 1967 -1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Human Relations Studies, Dept. of, 1968 - 1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Music Education, 1967 - 1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Music Education Facilities Plans, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Nurse Education, 1966 - 1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Physical Education, 1967 - 1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Rehabilitation, 1968 - 1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Religious Education, Dept. of, 1968 - 1969 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Secondary Education, Dept. of, 1967 - 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Administrative & Budgetary Memoranda: Social Studies, 1967 - 1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Series II: General Administrative Records
  - Administration & Supervision, Dept. of: Division Memoranda, 1968 - 1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Administration & Supervision, Dept. of: Division Publications, 1968 - 1970 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Administration & Supervision, Dept. of: Experienced Teacher Fellowship Program, 1968 - 1969 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Administration & Supervision, Dept. of: Puerto Rico Internship, July 1969 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Administration & Supervision, Dept. of: Miscellaneous, 1967 - 1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Announcements, Meetings, Etc., 1969 - 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report Materials, 1968 - 1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Christmas Party, 1963 - 1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Code 222: Publication Requests, 1966 - 1968 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Code 407: Correspondence, 1967 - 1968 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Code 407: Food Service, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Code 407: Paid Requests, 1967 - 1968 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Copies of Form Letters, 1967 - 1969 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Elliot Minenberg (personal), 1970 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - General Announcements, 1969-70 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Interoffice Communication, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Royfax Billings, 1970 - 1971 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Special Luncheons, 1967 - 1968 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Student Conduct and Discipline, 1969 - 1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Travel Reimbursement, 1968 - 1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Series III: School of Education Publications
  - School of Education Publications, 1967 - 1968 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - AAI (Afro-American Institute), 1968 - 1970 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - All-Square Student Affairs Newsletter, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Center Report, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - CAL (Council for Administrative Leadership) Newsletter, 1968 - 1969 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - COPES (Conceptually Oriented Program in Elementary Science) Newsletter, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Internal (Faculty and Administration Newsletter), 1969 - 1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - International Studies News, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - New Careers, 1968 - 1970 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Social Policy, 1968-70 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Staff Newsletter, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 14)